MANDIE WILLIAMS

Brooklyn, NY ◆ mandie.r.williams@gmail.com ◆ (918) 693-0178

QUALIFICATIONS PROFILE

Forward-thinking editor and creative marketing professional with a focus on beauty, fashion, and lifestyle. Exceptional aptitude for community and project management, with a focus on social media strategy and digital marketing innovation. Specializing in copywriting and content creation with additional skills in front end web development, analytics, and ecommerce.

EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND

New York Code + Design Academy

Web Development and Front End Development 101 course graduate, an intensive 16-week coding workshop focused on advanced front end web development skills.

University of Colorado at Boulder

Bachelor of Arts with Distinction, English Literature and History – College of Arts & Sciences, May 2011 Certificate in Advertising – School of Journalism & Mass Communication, May 2009 Graduating GPA: 3.8

University of Edinburgh: Semester Abroad, Fall 2010, concentration in Scottish Literature and Pictish History

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

SELL IT SOCIAL, LLC, NEW YORK, NY

Social Media Marketer, Rebel Circus, December 2014-March 2015

Analytics driven social media marketer for an ecommerce startup specializing in alternative apparel and accessories. Responsible for social media strategy and daily content creation across Facebook and Instagram. Worked closely with buyers and fulfillment team for integrated promotions and sales.

- Lead and execute content creation strategy for Rebel Circus's social media marketing across Facebook, Instagram, and the RebelCircus.com blog
- Generate social media reports, periodic social media audits, and regular analysis on key audience behavior metrics
- Measure, analyze, and report on digital marketing efforts, maintaining a detailed report of the consumer to continuously optimize content strategy
- Build and maintain relationships with blog and social media influencers in retro and alternative fashion, beauty, and lifestyle industries
- Manage customer service inquiries across social media platforms, working closely with the customer service team to maintain brand voice and best practices at all points of the consumer's experience
- Create and edit 40+ pieces of original and aggregated content daily

F+W MEDIA, A CONTENT AND ECOMMERCE COMPANY, BOULDER, CO AND NEW YORK, NY

Community Manager, BurdaStyle.com, June 2013-December 2014

Editorial team lead and chief social media strategist for the world's largest fashion sewing website. Responsible for day-to-day execution of the community roadmap and editorial calendar, social media growth, and cultivating strategic business partnerships with bloggers and advertisers.

- Set and implemented the social media strategy for BurdaStyle.com using all relevant social media platforms
- Developed strong brand partnerships, forged innovative business development opportunities, and pioneered sponsored content series now used company wide
- Collaborated with editorial team to optimize editorial content for community engagement and social media
- Developed and executed original editorial content, managed content calendar
- Worked closely with marketing team to craft and deploy sponsored content and campaigns
- Launched new digital products, including marketing and pricing strategy, based on community analysis

- Performed quantitative analysis of product performance, market and social media trends, and community engagement
- Engineer competitions and unique marketing campaigns to maximize affiliate traffic and increase revenue organically

BEAUTYSTAT.COM - New York, NY

Beauty Editor, January 2013-February 2014

Freelance contributor and beauty enthusiast connecting brands, media, and passionate consumers.

- Pitched, wrote and edited original beauty content including reviews, tutorials, and feature articles
- Represented BeautyStat at market events, maintain strategic brand and PR partnerships
- Innovated new ways to report and package beauty and wellness stories
- Built strategic brand partnerships and lasting relationships with media and PR contacts
- Optimized content for social media and SEO

THEGLOSS.COM - New York, NY

Associate Editor, Lifestyle and Beauty, October 2013-May 2014

Daily freelance contributor responsible for providing engaging, trend-driven content consistent with The Gloss's signature style and SEO best practices.

- Pitched, wrote, and edited original content, including dedicated articles, shopping roundups, and social media
- Performed market research and oversaw product selection for product guides and how-to articles
- Produced original content for feature articles and news coverage
- Ensured that the site reaches or exceeds monthly traffic goals with innovative, trend-focused, and challenging content
- Identified beauty, health, celebrity, fashion, and social trends for coverage
- Ensured all copy was on-brand, on-voice, grammatically clean, and edited for style

F+W MEDIA, A CONTENT AND ECOMMERCE COMPANY, BOULDER, CO AND NEW YORK, NY

Assistant Editor, Interweave Knits and knit.wear magazines, May 2011 – June 2013

Assisted in all aspects of publication for two seasonal lifestyle publications, including copy editing, department photography, technical editing, editorial planning, and full responsibility for all front of book pages.

- Conceived, assigned, edited and packaged ideas for all magazine departments, collaborating with executive and managing editors, as well as production and art departments
- Coordinated the copy, edit, photo and art department deadlines based on press schedules
- Routed copy, layouts and artwork through the editorial workflow process.
- Generated ideas and conceptualized stories for all magazine departments
- Studied market and industry trends, staying on top of new products, competitors, and emergent designers
- Executed FOB pages, including photography, with input from art department

RADIO 1190 – BOULDER, CO

Marketing Intern and Disc Jockey, May 2008 - May 2011

Managed all aspects of a weekly radio broadcast, including program development and sponsorship outreach. Responsible for guerilla marketing, event planning, and traditional PR for Radio 1190.

- Created a unique weekly broadcast and performed independently each week as a live radio host
- Developed extensive industry knowledge and a detailed picture of the competitive landscape
- Developed artist profiles, reviews, and catalogue contributions
- Built relationships and networked with sponsors, bands, and media
- Coordinated fundraising and community outreach events on campus and across Denver metro area
- Assisted PR Director with writing content, blogs, PR releases and alerts for station events

SKILLS

- Proficient in Adobe Creative Suite
- Familiarity with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bourbon library, and Bootstrap framework
- Expert in Chicago Manual of Style copy guidelines
- Typing Speed: 100 WPM